{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Sex lethal (sxl) in Drosophila is transcribed when", "opta": "the X autosome balance is less than 0.5", "optb": "the X autosome balance is 1 or greater", "optc": "the X autosome balance equals 0.5", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A mutation in the tip binding site of the repressor would result in", "opta": "constitutive trp operon expression", "optb": "inducible trp operon expression", "optc": "no operon expression", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The first protein complex to bind to the TATA box is", "opta": "transcription factor IIA", "optb": "transcription factor IIB", "optc": "transcription factor IID", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not part of the lac operon?", "opta": "I", "optb": "O", "optc": "P", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The lac operon is transcribed in which segments?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A frameshift mutation occurs in the sigma subunit gene transcribed as part of SPOl early genes. What will be the immediate result?", "opta": "Early genes will not be translated", "optb": "Middle genes will not be transcribed", "optc": "The bacterial host will lyse immediately", "optd": "Infection will proceed as usual", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the presence of high levels of tryptophan", "opta": "attenuator allows transcription of trp structural genes", "optb": "attenuator propogates transcription", "optc": "attenuator terminates transcription", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Tubulin is regulated by", "opta": "binding of tubulin to tubulin mRNA", "optb": "splicing of the tubulin transcript", "optc": "binding of tubulin to the tubulin translational product", "optd": "binding of tubulin to DNA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transcription factors are", "opta": "regions of DNA in the promoter area", "optb": "regions of DNA in the enhancer area", "optc": "any protein which binds to DNA", "optd": "proteins which bind DNAand initiate transcription", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Genes which need to be coordinately regulated but are not in operons may be regulated by", "opta": "common transcription factor binding domains", "optb": "TATA boxes", "optc": "CAAT regions", "optd": "GC regions", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are genes?", "opta": "The functional unit of inheritance", "optb": "A fragment of DNA", "optc": "A portion of a chromosome", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a transcription factor?", "opta": "Helix-turn-helix proteins", "optb": "Zinc finger proteins", "optc": "Leucine zipper proteins", "optd": "Steroid hormones", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sex determination in Drosophila involves", "opta": "alternate splicing", "optb": "methylation", "optc": "gene amplification", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Enhancers differ from promoters in that", "opta": "they initiate transcription", "optb": "they are adjacent to the start codon", "optc": "their orientation can be inverted without effect", "optd": "they are restricted to a specific gene", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Methylated gene are", "opta": "active", "optb": "silent", "optc": "dynamic", "optd": "either (a) or (b)", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following occur in the presence of glucose?", "opta": "lac Z gene expression is increased", "optb": "cAMP increases", "optc": "Binding of CAP-cAMP complex to the promoter area decreases", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sex hormones activate transcription of specific genes by", "opta": "binding to a transcription factor", "optb": "binding to RNA polymerase", "optc": "binding to DNA enhancer region", "optd": "binding to DNA promoter region", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The lac operon is translated into __________ proteins.", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the presence of tryptophan in the cell, the repressor is __________", "opta": "bound to tryptophan", "optb": "bound to DNA", "optc": "bound to both DNA and tryptophan", "optd": "bound to neither tryptophan nor DNA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Catabolite activating protein exerts __________ control on transcription of the lac operon genes.", "opta": "positive", "optb": "negative", "optc": "may be positive or negative", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "DNA is methylated at", "opta": "AC sequences", "optb": "TATA sequences", "optc": "CAAT sequences", "optd": "CG sequences", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why are several structural genes regulated as a unit in bacteria?", "opta": "An accident of evolution", "optb": "It allows coordinating regulation of genes with a common function", "optc": "The bacteria chromosome is so small; many different genes must be controlled by the same promoter", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Alternate splicing of RNA transcripts is a mechanism to regulate", "opta": "tubulin", "optb": "tachykinins", "optc": "DNA methylation", "optd": "leucine zippers", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}